Yong-Han Lin (she/her) A https://scod0401.github.io/ | ■ alberta410476@gmail.com

Research Interests

My research interests lie in the fields of human-computer interaction (HCI) and ubiquitous computing (UbiComp). I am interested in 1) investigating the well-being challenges in people's daily interactions and reliance on ubiquitous technologies and 2) designing and developing tools and interventions that promote digital well-being and mental health. My research goal is to support people's use of technologies for well-being in various contexts.

Education

National Yang-Ming Chiao-Tung University* (NYCU)

B.S. in Computer Science

Sept. 2018 - June 2022 Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Overall GPA: 3.84/4.3 | Major GPA: 3.91/4.3 | Last 60 Credits: 4.07/4.3
- **Selected Coursework**: Data Structures, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, User Experience & Usability Evaluation, CSCW Research Summer Institute

Research Experience

NYCU Mobile Ubiquitous Interaction Lab, Undergraduate Researcher/Research Assistant Advisor: Dr. Yung-Ju (Stanley) Chang

Sep. 2020 - Present Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Conducted a mix-method field study to understand the proposed mobile notification management features: pinning, sorting, categorizing [J.1]
- Studied users' perception of automatic, manual, and hybrid notification management modes, and the preliminary findings resulted in one poster paper at the 2023 UbiComp/ISWC conference [P.1]
- Led 3 college students and 1 graduate student to research and improve the design and features for an intelligent notification management system
- Built a notification management Android application that allows users to pin, sort, and categorize notifications, as well as predicts and presents users' preference on notifications' order by using BERT model and Flask

UC Davis Collaborative and Social Computing Lab, Research Intern

July 2022 - Oct. 2022

Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang and Dr. Yi-Chieh (EJ) Lee

Remote

• Researched peer-review systems and human-chatbot interaction and explored how human-chatbot collaboration supports peer assessment in education scenario to enable students to generate accurate and fair feedback

Polytechnique Montreal Human-Centered Design Lab, Research Intern

June 2021 - Jan. 2022

Advisor: Dr. Jinghui Cheng

Remote

• Conducted a qualitative content analysis and a statistical analysis to understand the usage, purposes, and impacts of visual artifacts in GitHub issue tracker system, the findings resulted in a paper at the 2022 EASE conference [C.1]

Peer-Reviewed Publications

(* indicates equal contribution)

[J.1] Pinning, Sorting, and Categorizing Notifications: A Mixed-methods Usage and Experience Study of Mobile Notification-management Features [In submission to ACM IMWUT '24 (Revision Cycle)] [paper]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Yung-Ju Chang.

[C.3] "I Want Lower Tone for Work-Related Notifications": Exploring the Effectiveness of User-Assigned Notification Alerts in Improving User Speculation of and Attendance to Mobile Notifications [In submission to ACM MobileHCI '24] [paper]

Tang-Jie Chang, Li-Ting Su, Yong-Han Lin, Jie Tsai, Zi-Xun Tang, Yung-Ju Chang.

[P.1] Automatic, Manual, or Hybrid? A Preliminary Investigation of Users' Perception of Features for Supporting

^{*}Former name: National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

Notification Management [paper]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Peng-Jui Wang, Yi-Chi Lee, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Adjunct Proceedings of the 2023 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing & the 2023 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computing* **(UbiComp/ISWC '23)**, pp. 98-102.

[C.2] Multiple Device Users' Actual and Ideal Cross-device Usage for Multi-Stage Notification-Interactions: An ESM Study Addressing the Usage Gap and Impacts of Device Context [paper]

Fang-Ching Tseng, Zih-Yun Chiou, Ho-Hsuan Chuang, Li-Ting Su, **Yong-Han Lin**, Yu-Rou Lin, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Uei-Dar Chen, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* **(CHI '23)**, pp. 1-15.

[C.1] Understanding the Characteristics of Visual Contents in Open Source Issue Discussions [paper][video]

Vishakha Agrawal*, **Yong-Han Lin***, Jinghui Cheng. In *Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on Evaluation and Assessment in Software Engineering* **(EASE '22)**, pp. 249-254.

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

NYCU CS 1270: Introduction to Database Systems (Spring 2022)

Instructor: Dr. Yi-Ju Tseng

Course Assistant

NYCU General Education: Critical and Creative Thinking (Spring 2021)

Instructor: Dr. Jonathon Hricko

Honors and Awards

Taiwan National Science and Technology Council Research Grant Award (Fall 2021)

Received a grant for doing research on studying users' perception of different notification management methods

Polytechnique Montreal Research Internship Scholarship (Summer 2021)

Paid for being a research intern during the summer

Volunteer and Leadership

Student Volunteer

CHI 2023, Hamburg

Provided support for paper session, hybrid Zoom meeting, and exhibit hall

CSCW 2022, Virtual

Monitored paper presentation video on YouTube livestream, and provided quick responses in GatherTown

Team Leader in Public Relation

Mei-Chu Hackathon 2020

Led a team of 6 students to contact corporate sponsorship and received 40K+ USD from Google, Amazon, etc

Other Work Experience

Software Engineering Intern

Xaduro Inc. (travel tech startup)

Jan. 2021 – June 2021 Taipei, Taiwan

- Collaborated with the engineering team to develop a travel agency system that allows 1K+ users by using MySQL, PHP, and JavaScript
- Optimized the hotel reservation system by fixing 80% of the usability issues detected from Google Search Console

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, R, Java, C++/C, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS

Tools: Android, Git, Firebase, Flask, Linux, LTFX